The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
Even within that brilliant history,
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
Despite being relatively unknown
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
and lacking a game record,
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
にもかかわらず—
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
A phantom sixth man.
幻のシックスマンがいた と
Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Now!
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
Thanks for the food!
（桜井(さくらい)）いただきまーす
（若松(わかまつ)）かわいいな オイ！
（桜井）え？
That's cute.
What?
妹のやつと間違えたとかか？
Did you take your little sister's by mistake?
Oh, sorry!
あっ すいません
But I made it myself, so I don't think I'd...
でも 自分で作ったから
間違えたりは…
You made it yourself?!
自分で作ったんだ！？
（青峰(あおみね)）お うまそーじゃん
（桜井）あっ
Hey, that looks good.
Aomine!
（若松）青峰！
Sup?
（青峰）うーす
Where have you been?
どこ行ってたんだよ オマエ！
You can't skip practice for no reason!
理由もなく 休んでんじゃねーよ
午後練は出んだろーな？
You're coming to practice this afternoon, right?
はっはー まっさかー
You can't be serious.
This is really good. Give me the rest of it.
てか うめーなコレ 全部よこせ
But this is...
（桜井）えっ あ いや これは…
（青峰）あ？
Huh?
Sorry, go ahead!
（桜井）すいません どうぞ
（若松）かー！
やってんじゃねーよ 桜井！
Don't give him that, Sakurai!
うっせーなぁ ちゃんとした
理由がありゃ 休んでいいんだな？
Shut up.
I can skip practice as long as I have a reason, right?
（青峰）
掘北(ほりきた)マイちゃんの写真集—
They said they'd confiscate my Horikita Mai photo book if I left it here.
おきっぱにしとくと
没収だってからよ
I just came to get this.
取りにきただけ
So I'm leaving.
なんで 帰るわ
お疲れ 頑張ってー
G'luck. Practice hard.
Wait, Aomine!
待てよ 青峰！
いーかげんにしろよ オマエ
練習出ろっつってんだろ！
Enough already!
I'm telling you to go to practice!
I'll forgive you once.
１回は許してやる 放せ
Let me go.
Wha—
（蹴る音）
（若松）なん…
（今吉(いまよし)）青峰！
Aomine!
I told him I'd do it.
（青峰）いや ちゃんと言ったし
“練習しろ 練習しろ”
笑わせんなよ
Practice, practice.
Don't make me laugh.
Ryo, how many points did I score last game?
良(りょう) オレ 前の試合
何点取ったっけ？
（桜井）えっ あの…
82点… です
Huh? Uh, 82 points.
Oops, I did it again.
あり？ また やっちまった
くっ はっははは…
I don't think you can practice with this thing.
これじゃ 練習とか中止じゃね？
Let's see, what was I trying to say?
あ えーと 何言おうと
してたんだっけ… あぁ
Oh, right.
You can talk after you're better than me.
オレより 結果出してから言えよ
ありえねーけど
Not that you ever will be.
（若松）くそっ…
Damn it.
（今吉）大丈夫か 若松
スマンのう
Are you okay, Wakamatsu?
Sorry about that.
なんで
キャプテンが謝るんスか？
Captain, why are you apologizing?
You're not wrong,
オマエは 間違(まちご)うてへん…
but don't say anything like that to Aomine again.
けど 青峰には 何も言わんとけ
Meritocracies are hardly unusual.
能力主義なんて
珍しいことやないやろ
けどっ…
But...
Do you know the golfer, Tiger Woods?
ゴルフのタイガー･ウッズって
知っとるか？
Huh?
（若松）は？
（今吉）じゃなきゃ アレや—
What about Shaq?
シャック
You mean Shaquille O'Neil?
シャキール･オニールっスか？
Yeah.
そうや
（今吉）タイガーが めっちゃ
ボール飛ばして勝ちまくるから—
Tiger won tons of games by hitting the ball too far,
so they extended courses and added regulations to keep him from driving so far.
コースが伸びて
クラブが飛ばんよう規制された
シャックもや
Shaq too.
He was too strong, so there was a drastic increase in rough play just to stop him.
パワーが ケタ外れ過ぎて—
ファウル覚悟で止める
ラフプレーが激増した
That's why they made the restricted area,
so the offense wouldn't be hit with charging fouls.
せやから オフェンスが
ファウルにならん—
ノーチャージエリアができたんや
スポーツの世界では
１人の選手があまりに強すぎて—
In the world of sports,
sometimes when a single player is too strong,
they change the rules.
ルールすら変えたっつうことがある
They're not common, but they really do exist.
まれに おんねん
もののたとえでのーて—
They're unfairly strong.
反則的に強い… そんなバケモンが
They're monsters.
Episode 15
Don't Make Me Laugh
（リコ）みんな！ 決勝リーグ
出場校 全部出たわよ！
Hey, guys! The names of all the schools appearing in the championship league are out!
As you can see,
見てのとおりだけど
Ａブロックはウチ—
Senshinkan
Meisei
Touou
Academy
Seirin
Touou
Academy
Meisei
Senshinkan
Seirin
A block is us, B block is Touou Academy,
Senshinkan
Ｂブロックは桐皇(とうおう)学園
Ｃブロックは鳴成(めいせい)—
Senshinkan
C block is Meisei, and D block is Senshinkan.
Meisei
Ｄブロックは泉真館(せんしんかん)—
Touou
Academy
These four schools will compete to represent our region.
この４校で
代表を争うことになるわ
（テツヤ２号(にごう)）くぅん
ハアハアハア
（日向(ひゅうが)）なんか
新鮮なリーグ表だなー
This is a different looking league chart.
Until last year, the Tokyo representatives
（伊月(いづき)）去年まで 東京代表は—
always included the three kings: Shutoku, Seiho, and Senshinkan.
秀徳(しゅうとく)･正邦(せいほう)･泉真館の三大王者で
決まりだったからな
I've been thinking...
（小金井(こがねい)）思ったんだけどさ—
We beat two of those teams, right?
そん中の２つには
オレら勝ったワケじゃん？
Do you think we could make it all the way this year?
今年は もしかして
行けちゃうんでないっ！？
（伊月）あ こいつ！
（日向）言いやがった！
You!
You said it!
だって 桃井ちゃんと
青峰がいる王者に負けても—
Even if we lose to the other king with Momoi and Aomine...
If we beat the others...
他に勝てば…
It's not Senshinkan.
（リコ）泉真館じゃないわ
What?
Those two go to Touou Academy.
（リコ）あの２人が行ったのは
桐皇学園よ
Seirin
Touou
Academy.......
Meisei
Senshinkan
Touou
Academy.....................
Meisei
Senshinkan
Touou
....Academy
Meisei
What?!
キセキの世代って—
I thought all the Generation of Miracles went to well-known schools!
みんな有名なトコ
行ったんじゃないの！？
I thought he would have gone to a strong school like Midorima.
てっきり 緑間(みどりま)みたく
王者のところかと…
I looked it up, so I'm sure.
ちゃんと調べたし 確かよ
聞いたことねーよ
I've never heard of them.
Their history isn't impressive,
過去の実績はほとんどないけど—
最近は 全国から
有望な選手を集めているそうよ
but they've been putting energy into their scouting efforts recently.
Touou
Academy
They've been recruiting promising athletes from all over the country.
ここ数年で
急激に力をつけてきて—
In the last few years, they've rapidly improved,
and this year's line up is comparable to Shutoku's.
特に 今年のメンツは
秀徳と比べても なんら遜色ないわ
（福田(ふくだ)）そんな…
I don't believe it...
Hey!
（火神(かがみ)）ウィース！
（小金井）あ 火神！
（日向）おせーな
Kagami...
You're late.
（火神）すんません
ちょっと掃除 長引いて…
Sorry.
Cleaning up took longer than expected.
（テツヤ２号）ワン！
Number 2?
２号？ ふぬ！？
（小金井）おっと
Kagami, did you play basketball?
火神君…
バスケした？
N-No.
え… いや
悪化してない？
You've gotten worse.
Well, I...
いやー その…
A little...
ちょっと…
You idiot, Kagami!
（リコ）こんの バカガミがぁっ！
（火神）すんまっ… だだだだっ！
Sorry, ow!
（リコ）あれほど言ったろーが！
その耳は飾りか！？
How many times did I tell you?!
Are your ears just for decoration?!
Are they just holes in your head?!
開いてんのはタダの穴か！？
Ow!
You'll just be watching today!
今日は見学ね！
保健室で シップもらってこい！
Get a heating pad from the nurse's office!
Since you can't sprint, walk all the way there on your hands!
ダッシュ！ …は無理だから
逆立ちで行け！
Seriously?
（火神）マジで！？
（黒子）火神君
Kagami.
Kuroko.
（火神）黒子… ふぅ
Kagami, you're stupid, but...
（黒子）火神君は バカですけど…
（火神）って いきなり オイ！
Where did that come from?
But I don't think you'd do something so reckless for no reason.
（黒子）なんの理由もなく
ムチャするとは思えません
Did something happen?
何か あったんですか
（リコ）ええぃっ
まったくもー バカガミ！
I don't believe that idiot!
Now, now, Coach.
まぁまぁ カントク…
んで 初戦の相手は？
So, who are we playing first?
火神君が不可欠だから
怒ってんのよ
I'm mad because we won't have Kagami!
Our first game is against Touou Academy!
初戦は桐皇学園！
I played Aomine.
（火神）青峰とやった
He said he used to be your "light."
そんとき 言ってた
ヤツは オマエの
昔の“光”だってな
ただ 同じチームだったって
言い方には聞こえねー
It sounded to me like you weren't just ordinary teammates.
What happened between you two in middle school?
オマエら 中学のとき
何が あったんだよ？
（黄瀬(きせ)）あっ！
（黄瀬）あー もう！ もっかい！
もっかいっス！
Oh, come on!
One more time! Just one more!
（青峰）ははっ あめーよ 黄瀬
You're naive, Kise.
Well, you play pretty well for someone who just started.
ま 始めたばかりで そんだけ
動けりゃ 大したもんだけどな
Kise's not doing bad against the ace, Aomine.
（先輩）黄瀬もよくやるなー
エースの青峰相手に…
つか 初心者だろ？
Isn't he a beginner?
I think he's got talent.
（さつき）才能あると思いますよー
He's tall, and he's a quick learner.
身長もあるし あの吸収力…
He might even become a great player!
すっごい選手になるかも！
（先輩）じゃあ青峰も その
センスを買って いつも相手を…
Then with his instincts, Aomine must be...
え それは… どうですかね
Well, I don't know about that.
He's just a longtime basketball junkie.
小さい頃からの
ただのバスケバカで…
（先輩）“バスケバカ”ねぇ
A junkie, huh?
Well, he does have more talent and practices harder than anyone on the team.
ま 確かに
才能も練習量もチーム一(いち)だ
はい あいつが一番—
Yeah.
Also, more than anyone else,
he loves basketball.
バスケが好きなんです
None of the Generation of Miracles
（黒子）“キセキの世代”も—
started off as extraordinary players.
初めから 並外れていたわけじゃ
ありません
ただ 青峰君が
その中で 一番早く—
However,
Aomine bloomed sooner
and more suddenly than the rest of us.
そして突然 開花しました
Aomine's amazing!
（観客１）すげぇ 青峰！
（観客２）１人だけぶっちぎってる
He's destroying them all by himself!
（観客３）あんなの
誰も止めらんねぇよ！
No one can stop him!
たあっ
Teiko
Yosen
（青峰）ほらよ
Here.
（黒子）青峰君 最近
練習休むことが増えましたね
Aomine, you've started skipping practice more lately.
Yeah, it's cool.
（青峰）あー いいんだよ
練習したら 上手くなっちまうだろ
If I practice, I'll get even better.
The harder I try, the more boring basketball gets.
頑張ったら 頑張った分だけ
バスケがつまんなくなってくんだよ
What I want must already be...
きっと
オレの欲しいもんは もう…
最近の青峰っち
強すぎてヤバくないっスか？
Don't you think Aominicchi's gotten real strong lately?
He must have so much fun with skills like those!
あんなんだと バスケが楽しくて
しょーがないスよ きっと！
I think it's just the opposite.
（緑間）むしろ
逆な気がするのだよ
What? Why?
え？ なんでっスか？
あいつは 誰よりも
バスケが好きであるがゆえに—
Not only does he love basketball more than anyone else,
but there is also something he desires more than anyone else.
誰よりも 欲しているものがある
自分と対等に
勝負ができるライバルだ
A rival who can stand as his equal.
However, he is too strong.
だが 今のあいつは強すぎる
He'll never find a rival with the current gap between himself and other players...
ライバルどころか まわりと
差が開き過ぎてしまったのだよ
圧倒的に…
being so overwhelmingly wide.
Basketball's just a game anyway.
（青峰）バスケなんて
結局 遊びだしな
I'm going to start skipping games too.
これからは
試合もテキトーに流して…
You can't do that.
（黒子）それはダメです
（青峰）んなぁ〜っ！？ アイス？
A popsicle?
It takes everything I have to keep up with everyone else,
ボクは いつも みんなに
ついていくので精一杯で—
青峰君の感覚は 分かりません
so I don't know how you feel, but...
けど—
どんなに 力が離れてても—
No matter how large the difference in our skill,
Loser
if I were your opponent,
ボクが相手なら
絶対にしてほしくないです
I would never want you to do that.
（黒子）それに 青峰君より
すごい人なんて すぐ現れますよ
Besides, I'm sure you'll meet someone more amazing than yourself soon.
You little jerk.
（青峰）こんのやろ… はははっ
そーだな
You're right.
That's right.
（黒子）そうです
That's his 40th point today!
（観客１）きたぁ 今日40点目！
（観客２）やっぱ すげぇ！
He really is amazing!
Aomine's really focused.
（さつき）すごい集中してる
青峰君！
His opponent is one of the best middle school forwards,
相手は 中学屈指のフォワード…
but he's crushing him!
なのに 圧倒してる！
All right!
よし！ はあ はあ
Huh?
What is this?
なんだよ それ…
もう戦うのも 諦めましたってか…
Have they given up already?
Is this what happens when I try even a little?
ちょっと マジメに
やったらこれか？
相手のやる気まで
失せちまったら—
If my opponents lose the will to play,
what's fun about basketball anymore?
もう バスケの何が楽しいんだよ
Tetsu,
（青峰）テツ
（黒子）ん？
（青峰）オマエの言ったことは
間違ってねぇと思う
I don't think you were wrong, but...
けど やっぱ—
I just can't.
ダメだわ
（黒子）え？
They all suck.
（青峰）どいつもこいつも
ヘボばっかだ
オレの欲しいもんは
絶対 見つかんねえ
I'll never find what I'm looking for.
オレに勝てるのは オレだけだ
The only one who can beat me is me.
We swept the tournament that year because of Aomine's strength.
（黒子）その年の大会は
青峰君の力で圧勝しました
けど それから
他の４人も変わっていって—
The other four started to change after that too.
３年の全国大会での
“ある出来事”をきっかけに—
Then because of a certain event at the national tournament in our third year,
I quit the Teiko basketball team.
ボクは 帝光バスケ部を辞めました
ふーん
まぁ ひと言
言わせてもらえば—
Well, if I could say one thing to him, it'd be,
調子のんなボケェ！
ってぐれーだわ！
"Don't get ahead of yourself, you idiot!"
It's boring because you're too strong?
“強くなりすぎて
つまんなくなった”？
"The only one who can beat me is me"?
“オレに勝てるのは オレだけ”？
The Generation of Miracles is full of those guys!
“キセキの世代”は
そんなんばっかか！
（火神）ヘソで コーヒー沸くぜ！
（黒子）お茶です
It's so funny I could bust a spleen!
You mean a gut.
Let's go beat him and wake him up.
（火神）さくっと勝って
目ぇ覚ましてやらぁ
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
The deciding game is today.
（さつき）今日… 決戦の日
約束します
青峰君に勝つと
I promise I will beat Aomine.
It's almost time.
（日向）いよいよだな
The championship league!
（伊月の母）決勝リーグ
（伊月）え？
What?
It starts today, doesn't it?
（伊月の母）今日からでしょ！
応援行くわね
I'll go cheer for you.
Since it's the championship league,
決勝リーグだから お化粧して！
I'd better put on my championship makeup!
（伊月）はぁ… 母さん…
Mom...
Thanks for the...
それ いただき！
（水戸部の弟妹たち）まーす！
...food!
Hey, those are my eggs!
（弟１）ちょ それ オレの玉子！
（弟２）あー もうウィンナーねぇ
We're out of sausages already!
（妹１）ああーん！
（妹２）みそ汁多い そっちがいい
This is too much miso soup! I want that one!
Rin, it's okay. You should eat.
（舞）凛(りん)にい いーよ 食べな
もう そろそろ行かないと
You have to go soon.
You're gonna be late, idiot!
（小金井の姉）
遅刻するよ バカたれ！
うぅん 姉ちゃん
もーちょい…
Just a little longer...
てか 試合は夕方から…
Besides, the game doesn't start until tonight.
（ハリセンでたたく音）
（姉）その前に学校あんだろっ！
You've got school before then!
You're really into this.
（景虎(かげとら)）熱心だな
（リコ）ぬわぁ！
Dad, can't you knock?
ちょっ パパ！ ノックしてよ！
いかんぞ 徹夜は！
美容によくない！
Don't stay up all night!
It's not good for your skin!
今日の相手 すごい強いのよ
Tomorrow's opponent is really strong.
I can't prepare too much.
やり過ぎってことは… ふわぁぁ
うーん… でも さすがに疲れたな
I guess I am tired though.
I should take a shower.
とりあえず シャワー浴びて…
（景虎）おい リコ
パンツ忘れとるぞ ぐわっ
Riko, you forgot your panties.
Get out of here, you pervert!
（リコ）はよ 出てけ！
この エロ親父！
See you...
Tsuchida
（土田(つちだ)）行ってきまー …ん？
Kitty!
（土田）ニャンコ〜
トーットットット…
（かみつく音）
（土田）痛ったぁー！？
Ow!
（火神）痛くねぇ
They don't hurt. They don't hurt!
痛くねぇぞ！
よっし…
All right!
Say your prayers, Aomine.
首洗って待ってやがれ 青峰…
絶対勝つ！
I will win!
Gymnasium
Event Schedule
Inter-High Preliminary Tournament Game
International Culture Festival 2012
Team Saizen
（高尾(たかお)）おーおー
A lot more people turn out for the championship league.
さすがに 決勝リーグともなると
人の数が違いますなー
（宮地(みやじ)）あれ？ 緑間は？
（高尾）あ うっす
Huh? Where's Midorima?
Midorima
Screw that. Not coming.
あははー 木村(きむら)！
パイナップル
Kimura, pineapple!
（木村）あるぜ 青々したやつ
Yeah, I've got a real green one.
Seirin
Touou
Academy
Meisei
Senshinkan
Seirin
Touou
Academy
Meisei
Senshinkan
The Senshinkan versus Meisei game should go to Senshinkan.
（大坪(おおつぼ)）泉真館 対 鳴成は
まず間違いなく泉真館だろう
The game that will shake the championship league
決勝リーグの行方を
左右するのは—
is Seirin versus Touou Academy.
誠凛(せいりん) 対 桐皇学園！
Touou Academy
Dressing Room
（さつき）えー！
青峰君が まだ来てない？
What?
Aomine's not here yet?
何度かけても でえへんのや
He won't answer no matter how many times I call.
That bastard...
あの野郎…
Sorry, sorry. It's my fault.
（桜井）すいません すいません
ボクが ふがいないばっかりに…
I'll try calling him!
（さつき）私 かけてみます！
There you are!
（さつき）出た！
（青峰）あい？
Sup?
What are you doing?
ちょっと 何やってんの
今どこ？
Where are you right now?
（青峰）何ってか 学校で…
Where? I'm at school.
Oh, sorry. I overslept.
ああ… ワリー 寝坊だわ
（さつき）寝坊？
（雑音）
You overslept?
（今吉）青峰
あと どれくらいで来られる？
Aomine, how long until you can get here?
（青峰）あ 今吉さん
Oh, Imayoshi.
まぁ 後半には… たぶん
I'll probably be there by the second half.
We're counting on you!
（今吉）頼むぞ オイ！
相手は あの誠凛なんやぞっ！
We're up against Seirin!
（青峰）はっはー またまた
There you go again.
あんなザコ倒すのに
20分でも多すぎだって
Twenty minutes is more than enough time to crush those scrubs.
Do whatever you can during the first half.
まー 前半はテキトーにヨロシク
（今吉）あ？ オイ…
What? Hey—
Seirin High
Dressing Room
It's almost time!
（リコ）そろそろ 時間よ！
Is everyone ready?
全員 準備はいいわね！
Only three out of the four schools will be going to the Inter-High!
インターハイに行けるのは
４校中３校！
Just like Koganei said,
小金井君も言ってたけど—
it doesn't seem difficult at first glance.
一見 難しくなさそうに
見えるわ けど…
However...
Huh? What? Hey, wait...
（小金井）んっ！？ えっ！？
何 ちょっ
（リコ）てぇぃっ！
（小金井）へぶっ！
If you think we can lose one because it's a league game,
リーグ戦だから
１敗までは大丈夫とか—
we're finished!
少しでも考えたら おしまいよ！
Why me?
なんで オレが？
It comes down to now!
大事なのは 今！
We will win this game!
この試合！ 絶対勝つ！
（リコ）誠凛ー ファイ！
（一同）オオ！
Seirin, fight!
（観客）おお 来た来た！
There they are.
誠凛と—
It's Seirin and Touou Academy!
桐皇学園！
Excuse me,
（火神）あの…
（若松）あ？
where's Aomine?
青峰は いないんスか？
That self-centered bastard is running late.
遅刻だよ あのジコチュー野郎は
Wha—
Sorry. We're actually in a bind without him too.
（今吉）すまんのー
あいつおらんと
ウチも困るんやけど
He said he'd show up around the second half.
後半あたりには 来るて
I guess you could call us the opening act.
ウチらは まぁ… 前座や
Go easy on us.
お手柔らかに頼むわ
（伊月）火神 もう青峰と
１回やったって？
Kagami, you've already played Aomine once, right?
モチベーション下がったとか
ないだろうな？
Your motivation hasn't dropped, has it?
（火神）まさか
No way.
If anything, I'm pissed!
むしろ
ブチギレてるよ です
こいつらが
前座だってんなら—
If these guys are the opening act,
I'll pull so far ahead that they can't catch up,
挽回できないまで 突き放して—
and turn their star into the world's biggest idiot!
世界一 マヌケな
主役にしてやらぁ！
I agree.
ボクも賛成です
青峰君は危険です 今のうちに
点差をつけたほうがいい
Aomine is dangerous.
We should score as much as possible while we have the chance.
There's no point in getting angry at someone who isn't here.
いない人に ムキになっても
意味はありません
目の前の相手がすべてです
The opponent in front of you is everything.
All right, you got it.
よし ちゃんと 分かってんな
Let's go all out...
スタートから…
（観客たち）うおおおぉーっ
（日向）全開だ！
right from the start!
（今吉）えい
（伊月）おっ！？
（水戸部）はっ…
（伊月）速いっ！
He's fast!
（日向）えぇぃっ
We'll break away now and take control of the game!
（日向）今のうちに 引き離して
流れを獲る！
You're quick, aren't you?
さっすが 戻り早いのー
We have no choice then.
ほなら しゃーないなっ！
（日向）なっ！
（今吉）まずはウチの—
We'll start by
having our suicidal member pave the way for us.
特攻隊長に 切り拓いてもらおか
（桜井）うっ すいません！
Sorry!
A three!
（日向）スリー！ モーションが
むちゃくちゃ速(はえ)ぇ！
His movements are incredibly fast!
It's not just No. 9, but the other four as well.
（伊月）９番だけじゃない
他の４人も…
They're not underestimating us.
油断していたわけじゃないが…
They're strong!
（火神）強(つえ)ぇ！
Calling yourselves the opening act was evil.
タチ悪いぜ マジ
前座なんてよ
What? I wasn't lying.
は？ ウソは ついてへんよ
You'll know once Aomine gets here.
青峰が来たら 分かるわ
We're cute little kids compared to him.
ワシらなんて
かわいーもんやで ホンマ
言うたやろ 前座やて
I told you, we're just the opening act.
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
Next Episode
（さつき）誠凛のみなさん
成長著しいですねー
All the Seirin players have shown significant growth.
Of course they have!
（リコ）とーぜんよ
But...
（さつき）でも…
（リコ）何？
What?
Riko, you don't seem to have grown.
（さつき）リコさんは
成長してないみたいですね
Episode 16
Let's Go
（リコ）
どこ見て 言ってんのよぉー！
What are you looking at?!